# **COLIN WILSON**

linkedin.com/in/colinwilsonseattle (425) 502-5582

cogawi@gmail.com Seattle, WA

Mechanical Engineer with expertise in structural design and analysis, and design for manufacturing. Master's Degree in Mechanical Engineering with a thesis focused on finite element analysis nanomaterials with both numerical and laboratory research work. I aim to use my research, design, and analysis backgrounds to develop the next generation of sustainable technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

# MASTER OF SCIENCE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Sep 2020 - Mar 2023

# Thesis: Large Strain Finite Element Analysis of Spinodal Shell Structures

- Created finite element analysis (FEA) models in Abaqus to replicate experimental results, helping to study fundamental material behaviors.
- Developed Python scripts for FEA postprocessing, to quantify structural behavior, stress distribution, and damage localization.
- Used MATLAB to generate FEA shell meshes of complex nano-architected materials.
- Studied nanomaterial behavior in harsh environments using dynamic and thermal FEA.

## **Courses and Projects:**

- Courses: Renewable Energy, Battery and Solar Cell Manufacturing, FEA, Elasticity, Composite Design and Analysis, Nanocomposites and Biocomposites.
- Research projects: Self-assembly and 3D printing of lithium-ion battery electrodes. Manufacturing and material properties of fungus and bacterial cellulose-based biocomposites.

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING *University of Washington, Seattle, WA*

Sep 2002 - Jun 2006

• Projects: Formula SAE drivetrain design, Fuel cell manufacturing capstone.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### DISCRETE LATTICE INDUSTRIES, Seattle, WA

Jun - Sep 2021

#### **Mechanical Engineer**

- Conducted trade studies on the use of a injection molded composite lattice structure in wind turbine blades.
- Performed FEA in Ansys and hand stress analysis to determine blade deflection and optimal structural parameters of a lattice-based wind turbine blade.
- Developed Python and MATLAB scripts for structural calculations and Ansys postprocessing.
- Used NuMAD for 3D modeling of the wind turbine blade and OpenFAST to conduct aerodynamic simulations.

#### KATERRA, Seattle, WA

*Mar 2019 – Jun 2020* 

#### **Manufactured Assemblies Design Engineer**

- Developed bathroom kits for residential buildings, to support factory assembly and cost reductions. Used SolidWorks to provide 3D models, BOMs and drawings.
- Built bath kit prototypes to test functionality, strength, and manufacturability.
- Used Catia 3DExperience scripting to automatically generate CAD models, drawings, and CNC files for factory-built wall panels.

#### SAFRAN AEROSYSTEMS, Everett, WA

*Apr 2015 – Mar 2019* 

#### **Design and Integration Engineer**

- Led design work on the 737 Airstair, developing design solutions within difficult constraints, and conducting prototyping and testing of the design to support on-time delivery.
- Investigate root cause of failed aircraft waste valves, disassembling failed samples to determine cause of failure, and testing to confirm the solution.
- Designed an aircraft galley drain system integrating structure, sensors, and plumbing.

COLIN WILSON Page 2

(425) 502-5582

linkedin.com/in/colinwilsonseattle

cogawi@gmail.com

#### BOEING COMMERCIAL AIRPLANES, Everett, WA

Sep 2006 - Nov 2012, Sep - Dec 2014

#### **Structural Design Engineer**

- Designed critical structural parts and assemblies on 747-8 and 767, using CATIA V5.
- Coordinated with production facilities from concept to production.
- Worked across groups and disciplines to manage design completion and define interfaces.
- Developed design solutions to factory production problems.

## KVICHAK MARINE INDUSTRIES, Seattle, WA

Nov 2012 - Jan 2014

# **Project Engineer**

- Developed structure and systems designs for aluminum hulled boats, for use in extreme environments.
- Worked from concept to production providing designs and drawings in Solidworks.

# **SKILLS AND INTERESTS**

- Finite element analysis (Abaqus, Ansys)
- Composite design and stress analysis
- Python, MATLAB
- Validation test design
- Mandarin Chinese professional working proficiency
- Mechanical design and CAD modeling (Solidworks, CATIA)
- Dedicated to working toward the clean energy transition.